《シカマル :
まさか 本体から離れた腕が➡
I can't believe his arm
could move on its own
単独で動くとはな…。
after being separated from his body...
だが いつの間に？
But when did this happen?
はっ 起爆札で 攻撃した
あのときか！
Was it back when
I attacked with a Paper Bomb?
煙にまぎれて 右腕を地面に…。
He hid in the smoke and
sent his right arm underground...
チッ… さすがに暁。
Tsk! Just what I'd expect of the Akatsuki.
They all use insane abilities!
いずれも
変わった能力者揃いだぜ》
(角都)
終わりだと言ってはいても➡
You said we were finished,
but my powers are still unknown to you.
オレの能力は
お前にとっては未知数…。
You keep your distance when
you make your next move.
ならば きちんと距離をとって
次の手を仕掛ける。
オレの連れと違って 賢い。
You're intelligent, unlike my partner.
(飛段)クソッ 体が！
角都 なんとかしろ!!
Damn it! My body...!
Do something, Kakuzu!
うっ しまった！
Oh no!
《今だ チョウジ！》
Now, Choji!
(チョウジ)肉弾針戦車！
Spiky Human Boulder!
(飛段)角都!!
Kakuzu!
《ヤマト : こ… これほどとは…》
S-Such power...
(サイ)ナルト
全然 休んでいないみたいだね。
It seems Naruto hasn't rested at all.
(サクラ)仕方ないわ 今すぐにでも
新しい術を完成させて➡
There's no choice.
He has to complete his new Jutsu
カカシ先生たちの増援に
向かわなきゃいないんだから。
and then we have to head out to
back up Kakashi Sensei and the others...
タイムリミットは 24時間か…。
The time limit is 24 hours, huh?
難しいことだけど
今は ナルトを信じるしかない。
It'll be tough, but all we can do
is believe in Naruto.
実際 私たち以上に
カカシ先生たちと➡
After all, there's nobody who
can work as smoothly
with Kakashi Sensei and
the others as us.
スムーズに連携がとれる班なんて
他にないんだしね…。
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
Kakuzu's Abilities
(ナルト)よし もうちょっとで
完成だってばよ！
All right. It's almost complete.
それに これで
サスケに追いつける…。
And now...
I can catch up to Sasuke.
確かにね。
Indeed you can...
ただし サスケの使う
火の性質変化には 気をつけろ。
However, watch out for Sasuke's
fire Change in Chakra Nature.
Huh?!
そろそろ五大性質変化の
優劣関係について➡
I guess I should explain
the comparative strengths of
the Five Great Changes in Nature to you.
説明しておいたほうが いいね。
なんだってばよ？ その優劣って。
What are... comparative strengths?
まぁ 言葉にすると 五つの
火 水 土 雷 風の性質変化は➡
Well, put simply, I guess it means
the five changes
in Chakra natures of fire, water,
earth, lightning and wind
それぞれ優劣の関係を持ち
繋がっているってところかな。
are each connected and
have comparative strengths.
だから どういうこと？
So... what does that mean?
それは 図で説明したほうが
わかりやすい。
It's easier to explain with a diagram.
五大性質変化は 五つ。
There are five main
Changes in Chakra Natures.
その五つを まずは➡
First you draw...
円を描くように描く。
うん。
FIRE
WATER
WIND
EARTH
LIGHTNING
... the five in a circle.
- Right.
でだ 例えば この最初の火。
And... for example,
take the first one, fire...
これに 優劣を書き込んでみるよ。
I'll draw comparative strengths
and weaknesses in this diagram.
これは 隣にある
風に対しては優勢。
This fire Change in Chakra Nature is
strong against the wind next to it,
反対側の
水に対しては➡
but weak against water
on the other side.
劣勢の立場にある
性質変化だ。
このように 五大性質変化には➡
The Five Great Changes in Nature
すべて 優劣の関係があるんだ。
have strengths and weaknesses
in relationship to each other.
う うん… そんで？
Uh... Okay. So?
《はぁ…
こりゃ わかってないな》
He's not getting it...
つまり 簡単に言うとだ➡
Simply put...
ナルト… お前の風遁の術は➡
Naruto...
your Wind Style Jutsu is weaker than
Sasuke's Fire Style Jutsu in relationship.
サスケの火遁の術に負けてしまう➡
関係性にあるってことだ。
えっ？
Huh?!
火遁に勝つには 水遁しかない。
Only Water Style can beat Fire Style.
なんで 風遁じゃ
火遁に勝てねえんだってばよ？
Why can't Wind Style beat Fire Style?
イメージしてみると早いかな。
It may be quicker to imagine them.
火は 風を受けると➡
Wood burns hotter when wind blows.
さらに激しく燃え上がる。
しかし 水をかけられると➡
However, the fire can be put out
when water is poured on it.
消えてしまう。
つまり サスケの火遁の術に➡
That means if you strike
one of Sasuke's Fire Style Jutsu...
同等レベルの風遁の術をぶつければ➡
with a Wind Jutsu of the same strength,
さらに でかい火遁になって
返ってくるわけだ。
it'd backfire by making
the fire even larger.
ただし 風の上下を見てみろ。
However, look at
the relationship of wind.
風は 確かに火には弱いが
雷には強い。
Wind is indeed weak against fire,
but it is strong against lightning.
つまり お前の新術は➡
In other words,
that means your new Jutsu...
サスケの雷遁 千鳥に強いってことだ。
will be strong against Sasuke's
Lightning Style Chidori.
ナルト… お前➡
Naruto...
It's a good thing you don't have
the earth Change in Chakra Nature.
土の性質変化じゃなくて
よかったな。
オレってば サスケとの相性
よかったんだな。
So I'm a good match with Sasuke, huh?
ああ。 雷に勝てるのは 風だけだ。
Yes, only wind can defeat lightning.
いや そっちじゃなくて。
え？
No, that's not what I meant.
Hmm?
火を助けて➡
I mean only the power of wind
can help fire
さらに大きな力にできるのは➡
風の力だけだ ってことだ。
by making it an even larger power.
(ヤマト)ああ そうだな。
Yeah, that's right...
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto!
アンタ すごいじゃない。
ああ。
You're awesome.
Yeah!
修業… 順調そうですね。
It looks like your training
is going well.
まあな。
じゃあ もうすぐ できるのね？
I guess.
Then you'll be finished soon, right?
うん。
いや ちょっと待て。
Yeah.
No, just a minute.
もう少し時間をくれないか？
Could you give me a little more time?
まだ 試しておきたいことがある。
There's still something
I want to test out.
(チョウジ)どういうことなの？
What's going on?
やっぱり
ライドウ先輩の言ったとおりか…。
I knew it.
It's just as Raido Senpai said...
おそらく 体を硬化する術だ。
It might be a Jutsu
for hardening his body.
それが アイツの能力。
That's his power...
よく分析している。
Nice analysis...
そうだ。 オレには
どんな物理攻撃も通じない。
That's right.
No physical attack will work on me.
《ある程度の予測はしていたが
これほどまでとは…。
I'd projected their powers
to a certain degree, but this...
直接攻撃がきかねえとなると
どうする…》
If we can't use direct attacks,
what should we do?
シカマル…。
Shikamaru...
フフッ アハハハハ！
驚け！ 無神論者ども！
Be afraid, you atheist jerks!
よっしゃ！
そろそろ 反撃といこうぜ！
All right! It's about time for us
to counterattack!
角都！
さっさと この術を外してくれ！
Kakuzu, break this Jutsu already!
あぁ…。
Sure...
おっ！
バカな！ 気配もなく
このオレの背後から。
It can't be...
You snuck up behind me...
without me sensing you...
うぅ…！
(カカシ)残念だったな。
Too bad...
フフッ アハハハハ！
驚け！ 無神論者ども！
Be afraid, you atheist jerks!
よっしゃ！
そろそろ 反撃といこうぜ！
All right! It's about time for us
to counterattack!
角都！
さっさと この術を外してくれ！
Kakuzu, break this Jutsu already!
あぁ…。
Sure...
おっ！
バカな！ 気配もなく
このオレの背後から。
It can't be...
You snuck up behind me
without me sensing you...
うぅ…！
残念だったな。
Too bad...
《いの : すごい！》
Awesome.
What?! What's up with that?!
はあ？ なんだよ それ！
お前！ 物理攻撃
きかねえんじゃなかったのか？
I thought physical attacks
weren't supposed to work on you!
そうだ！ カカシ先生は
どうやって アイツを？
Yeah! How did you get
behind him, Kakashi Sensei?!
すべて見せてもらった。
お前の体を硬化する術。
I saw everything.
I saw the Jutsu you use
for hardening your body.
(カカシ)さっき結んだ印から見て
土遁の性質変化だ。
Judging from how you formed
your seal earlier,
I'd say you've got an
earth Change in Chakra Nature.
(角都)あの一瞬で
オレの印のスピードを見切っただと!?
In that instant...
you read the speed of my seal?
それに これほどの雷遁を…。
And using Lightning Style at this level...
そうか！ お前が
写輪眼のカカシ！
I see!
You're... the Sharingan Kakashi...
(カカシ)土は雷に弱い。
Earth is weak against lightning...
相性が悪かったな。 終わりだ。
We're not a good match...
You're finished.
《やっぱり すごい カカシ先生は。
Kakashi Sensei is awesome,
sure enough!
Now there's just the other one!
これで あとは もう一人》
(チョウジ)一瞬で…。
さすが カカシ先生だね。
In an instant...
Just what I'd expect from Kakashi Sensei!
あぁ 不死身じゃないほうを
先にやっておかないと➡
Yeah. We needed to take care
of the mortal one first...
やっかいだからな。 うっ！
It'd be trouble, after all.
大丈夫？ シカマル。
You okay, Shikamaru?
(シカマル)そろそろ やべぇかもな。
This isn't looking good.
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
《影真似は もう限界だな》
His Shadow Possession
has reached its limit, huh?
うっ… うぅっ…。
心臓を ひと突きかよ…。
He nailed your heart in one shot?
いきなり やられてんじゃねえよ！
ったく…。
How can you get hammered
right off the bat like that?!
For crying out loud...
次は お前だ。
You're next.
《決まった！》
It's over!
ぐおっ…。
《えっ!?》
ふん…。
あ～あ かっこつけて 「終わりだ」
とかって言ってたのにな。
Oh, boy.
And here you acted all cool and
said, "You're finished."
《どういうことだ…》
What's going on...?
ゴホッ…。
《急所は外れていないはず…》
I'm sure I didn't miss the vital spot.
よっしゃ さっさとケリつけようぜ。
All right, let's settle this right now.
そのつもりだ。
I intend to!
(角都)ぐっ… ぐうっ…。
チッ… 影真似も限界だ。
My Shadow Possession
has reached its limit...
うおおお!!
ねぇ シカマル… どうなってるの？
Hey, Shikamaru.
What's happening?
それに さっき
雷切が当たったはずなのに➡
And why didn't he die even though...
the Lightning Blade nailed him?
なんで死なないの？ アイツ…。
さぁな… けど アイツら相手じゃ➡
Who knows...?
But with these guys,
it would take a lot to surprise me now.
少々のことじゃ
驚かなくなってきたぜ。
Oh, boy...
あ～あ…。
やっと動けるぜ。
I can finally move...
《なんだ？ あれは…》
What're... those?
さて… じゃ やるか？ 角都。
Now... shall we do this, Kakuzu?
あぁ。
Sure...
《な… 何？ あれ…。
Wh-What're those?!
すごくイヤなチャクラの感じ…》
That Chakra feels awful...
ククククク… ジャシン様！
見ててくださいよ!!
Lord Jashin! Watch me!
オレ 本気出すから！ マジ本気！
I'm going to get serious! I mean it!
腸とか引きずり出すからよぉ!!
I'll rip out their guts!
気をつけろ チョウジ。
うん。
Watch out, Choji!
Right.
何だ？
What...?
(飛段)角都！ おい おい…！
Kakuzu! Hey! Hey! Hey!
タンカきったそばから いきなり
１匹死んでんじゃねえかよ！
One of them died right after
our verbal assault!
ホント カッコつかねえな おい！
God, you really stink!
《ヤツの体から出てきた面が
１つ斃れたってことは➡
Since one of the masks that
came out of his body died...
さっきの雷切で 仕留めたのは➡
it must've been that mask I hit
with my Lightning Blade earlier.
あの面ってわけか…。
少し ネタがありそうだな》
Looks like we got something here.
飛段 少し下がってろ。
Hidan, stand down for a while.
I'll take care of this.
ここは オレがやる。
ちょっ！ 待て待て！
Hey... Just a minute!
さっきから
ずっと やられっぱなしで➡
We've been getting our butts kicked
the whole time and it's ticking me off.
イライラしてんだぜ オレは。
ヘッ いつものでいこうぜ。
Let's go with the usual.
フン。
なっ…？
(角都)風遁 圧害！
Wind Style: Pressure Damage!
チョウジ 気をつけろ！
お～っ！
Choji! Watch out!
(チョウジ)クッ…。
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
《いの : そんな 自分の味方ごと？
No way...
He even attacked his own partner?!
そうか 不死身を利用して…》
I get it! He's taking advantage
of the immortality!
くるぞ チョウジ。
クッ…。
Here he comes, Choji!
ダメ… あんなの
まともにくらったら…。
No... If they are hit head-on with that...
チョウジ シカマル 逃げて！
Choji, Shikamaru! Run!
雷遁 偽暗！
Lightning Style: False Darkness!
チッ！
間に合わねえ！
I won't make it in time!
危ない！
Look out!
カカシ先生…！
Kakashi Sensei...!
大丈夫ですか？
ま… なんとかな。
Are you okay?
Well... somehow, I guess...
《コイツら… 強い…。
These guys... are powerful...
特に あのマスクのほうが…。
That masked guy in particular...
しかし これだけ 高レベルの術は➡
But no one should be able
to use such high-level Jutsu
己の持つチャクラの性質と
合致しないと出せないはず。
unless they are compatible with
that person's own Chakra nature.
それを 土 風 雷の３つも…。
And he uses earth, wind and lightning...
いったい どういうことだ？》
What the hell is going on?
驚いたな… この段取りで
殺せなかったのは➡
I'm surprised...
You're the first one we weren't able
to kill with this combination...
お前が初めてだぜ… はたけ カカシ。
Kakashi... Hatake.
写輪眼で見切ったか。
だが 次のはどうだ？
So you read it with your Sharingan, huh?
However...
How about this next attack?!
なに!?
What?!
火遁 頭刻苦！
Fire Style: Searing Migraine!
what made me think
kondo wa itsu aeru ka nante
how can you say that with a straight face
sonna kao shite yoku ieru tte
when you asked we will meet again
omotteta yo nande darou
any time you talk to much I don't get it
any time shaberisugi no k y
for a moment I see your bluff and I cry
chirari miseru tsuyogari na i cry
do my tears even work on you?
namida no kouka wa dore kurai
I keep saying "I want to be loved"
watashi nari ni aisaretai
in my own special way but you still don't get the hint
afureru no ni kimi ga mienai
this nagging feeling I feel
nidoto kimi ni aenai
that I'll never see you again...
sonna ki ga suru nda
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie
watashi tabun uso demo ii no ni
I can't even say "don't leave me"
ikanaide mo ienai yo
when you let go of my hand
nigitteta te ga hanaretara
will you forget someday?
kimi wa itsuka wasurechau no
(ガイ)サイ君 こんなとこで
何してるんだ？
ちょっと 絵を…。
(ガイ)なんだ なんだ 元気がないな。
about me
watashi no koto
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai watashi tabun
顔色 わりぃぞ。
元々です。
熱き血潮は青春の証し。
キミは 熱血が少し足りないようだ。
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie 'cause I can't even say "don't leave me"
uso demo ii no ni ikanaide mo ienai yo
よし！ とっておきのアイテムを
プレゼントしよう！
これだ！
なんですか？ それ。
このスーツはな 通気性 保湿性に優れ
抜群のフィット感を実現した➡
Next Episode
究極のボディースーツなのだ。
もちろん オレも愛用している。
Our best plan would be
to attack them separately.
If we're going to do that,
we'll need to stall Hidan...
欲しくても 手に入らない
非売品だ。
Then I'll do it with
my Mind Transfer Jutsu.
見よ！ この美しいボディーラインを！
No. It's too risky.
修業のときに これを着れば
クセになること間違いなし！
Then I'll do it.
That won't do, either.
まさに 青春が生んだ
奇跡の一品だ！
We'll be finished if we approach him
and he gets some of our blood.
奇跡の一品？
ここだけの話だが➡
But...
I'll capture him by myself...
And I'll fulfill that role.
ナルトも リーも このスーツのおかげで
強くなったんだぞ。
ナルトも!?
The Terrifying Secret
Next time: "The Terrifying Secret"
というわけなんだけど
似合うかな？
はっきり言って ダサッ！
Sai, what're you doing here?
Just drawing a picture.
Hey. You don't look well.
You look pale!
I always look like this.
A burning vigor is a sign of youth!
It appears you're lacking
some enthusiasm!
All right! I'll present you with
a very special item!
Here it is!
What's that?
This ultimate suit has excellent breathability
and moisture-retaining properties
and fits perfectly.
Of course, I always use it.
This is a highly sought-after item
that's really hard to get!
Look at these beautiful body lines!
Once you wear this during training
you won't be able to stop!
This is truly a miracle product
brought about by youth!
Miracle product?
This is a secret, but...
Naruto and Lee got stronger
because of this suit!
Naruto too?
And that's what happened
So, how does it look?
To be straight with you, it looks geeky.
What?!